# Michael Arvelo

Phone: (407) 963-2618 | Email: michaeldevelopscode@gmail.com |

Address: ALTAMONTE SPRINGS, FL 32701 |
GITHUB: https://github.com/MichaelDevelopsCode |

LINKEDIN: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-arvelo-169925148/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-arvelo-169925148/</a> | PORTFOLIO: <a href="https://michaeldevelopscode.github.io/dev-portfolio2.0/">https://michaeldevelopscode.github.io/dev-portfolio2.0/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-Stack Web Developer looking for a place to develop, continue to grow, and connect with other developers. Over 3 years of experience learning web development, developed quality skills in communication, collaboration, and problem solving. Recently received a Certificate in Full-stack web development from the University of Central Florida,

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

• Tools: Git, Heroku

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Databases: MySQL, GraphQL, SQL, MongoDB

• Libraries & More: ¡Query, React, AJAX, JSON, Node.js

## **PROJECTS**

PhotoHut, Live site: <a href="https://ucf-photo-hut.herokuapp.com/">https://ucf-photo-hut.herokuapp.com/</a>

Git repo: https://github.com/Azambik/Photo-Hut

Community site for professional photographers using a comment and voting system.

Website utilizing both front-end and backend.

Languages and tools: Node.js, express, handlebars, routes, mysql for the database, and

more.

## **Plan Your Date Night**

Live site: <a href="https://michaeldevelopscode.github.io/plan-your-date-night">https://michaeldevelopscode.github.io/plan-your-date-night</a>
Git repo: <a href="https://github.com/MichaelDevelopsCode/plan-your-date-night">https://github.com/MichaelDevelopsCode/plan-your-date-night</a>
Web application for meal and cocktail pairing recipes for your date.

Users can generate a full meal and drink pairing and get the tools necessary for shopping and preparing their night.

Languages and tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, Foundation, and APIs.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Cubic Simulation Systems Inc, Orlando. FL 32809

Software developer intern

MAY 2018 - MAY 2019

- Created first of many applications pushed to production in just the first three days
- Exceeded project expectations working in a cross-functional environment, coordinating with developers, subject matter experts, and producers..

- Participated in code reviews, pair programming, refactoring, and bug fixing, minimizing errors and increasing overall efficiency.
- Extended internship from 3 months to a full year

# **LAV Productions LLC**, Orlando FL — *AV Technician*

DEC 2015 - AUG 2017

- Installed, set up, stored and maintained audio/visual equipment while operating and troubleshooting technical problems as they occur
- Elminated reoccuring technical dificulties, increasing productivity.
- Promoted to team lead

# **EDUCATION**

**UCF**, Orlando FL — Full Stack Developer Bootcamp Certificate

OCT 2020 - APRIL 2021

Graduate of UCF Full-stack development bootcamp program